Register of the Eric Voegelin papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence (Alphabetical File), 1928-1984
  - Tsatsos, Themistokles (4), 1954-1966 (Box-folder 38: 3)
  - Uitgiverij Paul Brand N.V. (2), 1957 (Box-folder 38: 4)
  - Ullrich, Luise (4), 1971-1976 (Box-folder 38: 5)
  - Unabhängige Zeitschrift für Philosophie/The Independent Journal of Philosophy (4), 1980 (Box-folder 38: 6)
  - Unger, Annie and Fritz (2), 1940 (Box-folder 38: 7)
  - United States. Consulate (Vienna) (1), 1938 (Box-folder 38: 8)
  - United States. Department of State. Passport Division (2), 1948 (Box-folder 38: 9)
  - United States Information Service. Foreign Service, 1958-1959
    Correspondence regarding lectures of Eric Voegelin at different Amerika-Haus locations.
    - Darmstadt (2) (Box-folder 38: 10)
    - Essen (4) (Box-folder 38: 11)
    - Hannover (6) (Box-folder 38: 12)
    - Munich (3) (Box-folder 38: 13)
    - Nuremberg (16) (Box-folder 38: 14)
    - Tübingen (20) (Box-folder 38: 15)
  - United States. War Department. Military Intelligence Division (R. Taylor Cole) (2), 1942 (Box-folder 38: 16)
    Includes Eric Voegelin's comments on military operations and psychological warfare in Germany
  - Universität München (8), 1960-1966 (Box-folder 38: 17)
  - University of Alabama (4), 1940-1952 (Box-folder 38: 18)
  - University of California at Los Angeles (Bennet M. Allen, Raymond G. Gettel) (5), 1938 (Box-folder 38: 19)
  - University of Chicago (Harold D. Lasswell) (8), 1938 (Box-folder 38: 20)
  - University of Chicago Press (88), 1950-1981 (Box-folder 38: 21)
    Includes contract and correspondence with the Walgreen Foundation (Jerome G. Kerwin)
  - University of Maryland (Walter Darnell Jacobs) (2), 1966 (Box-folder 38: 22)
  - University of Michigan (Clarence S. Yoakum) (2), 1938 (Box-folder 38: 23)
  - University of Michigan Press (Fred D. Wieck) (4), 1955 (Box-folder 38: 24)
  - University of Minnesota (William Anderson) (2), 1938 (Box-folder 38: 25)
  - University of Notre Dame Press (Bruce M. Fingerhut) (25), 1961-1978 (Box-folder 38: 26)
    Includes correspondence with R. Piper & Co. Verlag
  - University of Saint Thomas, Houston (Thomas J. Bole III) (21), 1965-1967 (Box-folder 38: 27)
  - University of Sussex, Great Britain (14), 1965-1966 (Box-folder 38: 28)
    Includes correspondence with G. R. Urban, and regarding the European Seminar, 1966
  - University of Texas at Austin (Bruce F. Grube) (5), 1975-1977 (Box-folder 38: 29)
  - University of Washington Press (Donald R. Ellegood) (5), 1966-1969 (Box-folder 38: 30)
  - Uppsala University, Sweden (Ivan Engnell, Harald Riesenfeld) (4), 1956 (Box-folder 38: 31)
  - Vahanian, Gabriel (18), 1967 (Box-folder 38: 32)
  - Valjavec, Fritz (5), 1959 (Box-folder 38: 33)
  - Vatikiotis, P. J. (24), 1965-1974 (Box-folder 38: 34)
  - Vazquez, Edward H. (2), 1969 (Box-folder 38: 35)
  - Vecchio, Giorgio del (1), 1961 (Box-folder 38: 36)
  - Veit, Otto (3), 1960 (Box-folder 38: 37)
  - Verdross-Drossberg, Alfred von (32), 1938-1961 (Box-folder 38: 38)
  - Verlag Anton Pustet (Erich Lampey) (31), 1959-1964 (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Verlag Herder (7), 1964-1965 (Box-folder 39: 2)
  - Verlag Lambert Schneider (Lothar Stiehm) (2), 1981 (Box-folder 39: 3)
  - Verlag W. Kohlhammer (Anneliese Heiss) (5), 1963 (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - Verlag Styria (Gustav E. Kafka) (11), 1955-1957 (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - Verlagsanstalt Benziger & Co. (Otto Bettschart) (36), 1957-1960 (Box-folder 39: 6)
  - Viehweg, Theodor (Archiv für Rechts- und Sozialphilosophie) (5), 1958-1962 (Box-folder 39: 7)
  - Viking Press (1), 1951 (Box-folder 39: 8)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review (Charlotte Kohler) (8), 1968-1971 (Box-folder 39: 9)
  - Vivas, Eliseo (5), 1966-1970 (Box-folder 39: 10)
  - Voegelin, Hermann and Irmgard (4), 1958-1971 (Box-folder 39: 11)
  - Voice of Austria (Franz Klein) (1), 1943 (Box-folder 39: 12)
  - Volker Fund. See William Volker Fund
  - Volker, Margret (1), 1962 (Box-folder 39: 13)
  - Von Sivers, Peter and Judy (63), 1967-1982 (Box-folder 39: 14)
  - Vondung, Klaus (61), 1970-1983 (Box-folder 39: 15)
  - Vree, Dale (4), 1974-1976 (Box-folder 39: 16)
  - Waal, Elizabeth de (56), 1938-1976 (Box-folder 39: 17)
    See also Incremental correspondence (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Wacquez, Janine (2), 1967 (Box-folder 39: 18)
  - Waelder, Robert and Jenny (16), 1936-1950 (Box-folder 39: 19)
  - Wagner, Fritz (6), 1966-1972 (Box-folder 39: 20)
  - Wagner, Helmut H. F. (5), 1960 (Box-folder 39: 21)
  - Wagner, Helmut R. (22), 1974-1978 (Box-folder 39: 22)
  - Waldman, Eric (15), 1960-1964 (Box-folder 39: 23)
  - Waldstein, Wolfgang (3), 1967 (Box-folder 39: 24)
  - Wall, Kevin (3), 1980-1982 (Box-folder 40: 1)
  - Walsh, David (18), 1972-1984 (Box-folder 40: 2)
  - Walter, Robert (Hans Kelsen-Institut) (9), 1973-1974 (Box-folder 40: 3)
  - Walter-Raymond-Stiftung (Ludwig Vaubel) (1), 1964 (Box-folder 40: 4)
  - Warth, Hermann
    - 1966-1971 (Box-folder 41: 1)
    - 1972-1980 (Box-folder 41: 2)
  - Wasinger, Stephen (6), 1970-1971 (Box-folder 41: 3)
  - Watanabe, Michael S. (1), 1971 (Box-folder 41: 4)
  - Webb, Eugene (22), 1974-1983 (Box-folder 41: 5)
  - Weber, Adolf (1), 1962 (Box-folder 41: 6)
  - Weber, Marianne (2), 1936 (Box-folder 41: 7)
  - Weber-Schäfer, Peter (45), 1963-1978 (Box-folder 41: 8)
  - Weinberger, Herr (1), 1949 (Box-folder 41: 9)
  - Weinwurm, Ernest H. (9), 1939-1944 (Box-folder 41: 10)
  - Weisskopf, Viktor (2), 1976 (Box-folder 41: 11)
  - Weisskopf, Walter A. and Gertrude (29), 1939-1982 (Box-folder 41: 12)
  - Weizsäcker, Carl Friedrich von (2), 1966 (Box-folder 41: 13)
  - Weller, LeGrand J. (5), 1960 (Box-folder 41: 14)
  - Wessell, Leonard P., Jr. (4), 1977-1981 (Box-folder 41: 15)
  - Westdeutscher Verlag (Friedrich Georg Middelhauve)(20), 1965-1966 (Box-folder 41: 16)
  - White, Edward A. (1), 1975 (Box-folder 41: 17)
  - Whitton, John B. (Geneva Research Centre) (6), 1938 (Box-folder 41: 18)
  - Wickerhauser Lederer, Gertrud (2), 1940 (Box-folder 41: 19)
  - Wiehl, Reiner (4), 1974-1975 (Box-folder 41: 20)
  - Wiese, Leopold von (28), 1928-1934 (Box-folder 41: 21)
  - Wilde, Johannes (2), 1939-1955 (Box-folder 41: 22)
  - Wildung, Dietrich (2), 1971 (Box-folder 41: 23)
  - Wilhelmsen, Frederick D. (2), 1967-1970 (Box-folder 41: 24)
  - Willfort, Rita (22), 1938-1980 (Box-folder 41: 25)
  - William Volker Fund (Richard C. Cornuelle, Kenneth S. Templeton, Jr., H. W. Luhnow) (77), 1953-1960 (Box-folder 42: 1)
  - Williams, Arnold (3), 1977-1978 (Box-folder 42: 2)
  - Williamson, René de Visme (8), 1956-1974 (Box-folder 42: 3)
  - Wilson, A. J. (2), 1980 (Box-folder 42: 4)
  - Wilson, Francis G. (11), 1953-1962 (Box-folder 42: 5)
  - Winckelmann, Johannes (1), 1967 (Box-folder 42: 6)
  - Winge, John H. (1), 1940 (Box-folder 42: 7)
  - Winkler, Hans Joachim (1), 1969 (Box-folder 42: 8)
  - Winter, E. (2), 1966 (Box-folder 42: 9)
  - Winternitz, Emanuel (114), 1938-1976 (Box-folder 42: 10)
  - Wiser, James L. (8), 1975-1982 (Box-folder 42: 11)
  - Wissenschaftliche Buchgesellschaft (8), 1970-1974 (Box-folder 42: 12)
  - Wittfogel, Karl H. (2), 1963 (Box-folder 42: 13)
  - Woellner, Brigitte (1), 1975 (Box-folder 42: 14)
    Cousin once removed of Eric Voegelin (daughter of Fritz and Leni Rühl).
  - Wolff, Kurt H. (5), 1949-1950 (Box-folder 42: 15)
  - Wolfson, Harry A. (1), 1961 (Box-folder 42: 16)
  - Wunderlich, Eva C. (2), 1946-1948 (Box-folder 42: 17)
  - Yale University (Edwin M. Borchard) (13), 1938-1939 (Box-folder 42: 18)
  - Young Americans for Freedom (2), 1971 (Box-folder 42: 19)
  - Zeitschrift für Politik (Helmut Kuhn, Hans Maier, Alfred Jüttner) (3), 1964-1974 (Box-folder 42: 20)
    Includes correspondence with F. Knöpfle
  - Zijderveld, Anton C. (2), 1971 (Box-folder 42: 21)
  - Zimmermann Büttner, Charlotte (21), 1956-1975 (Box-folder 42: 22)
  - Zinoviev, Alexandre (2), 1981 (Box-folder 42: 23)
  - Zisch, Wolfgang (1), 1976 (Box-folder 42: 24)
  - Zolla, Elémire (10), 1971-1981 (Box-folder 42: 25)
  - Zucker, Wolfgang M. (4), 1969 (Box-folder 42: 26)
- Correspondence (Chronological File), 1969-1974
  Mostly outgoing day files, arranged chronologically
  - 1969 July-December (Box-folder 43: 1-6)
  - 1970 (Box-folder 43: 7-18)
  - 1971 (Box-folder 44: 1-12)
  - 1972 (Box-folder 45: 1-12)
  - 1973
    - January-May (Box-folder 45: 13-17)
    - June-December (Box-folder 46: 1-6)
  - 1974 January-October (Box-folder 46: 7-16)
- Speeches and Writings, 1921-1987
  Conference papers, drafts of books, essays, notes, reviews, speeches, and related correspondence, arranged chronologically. See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, Honorary degrees; and CORRESPONDENCE, American Sociological Review, United States Information Service.
  - "Allgemeines Staatsrecht,", undated (Box-folder 47: 1)
    Outline for a projected book
  - "Astrology and Politics,", undated (Box-folder 47: 2)
    Outline
  - "Cycle Theory and Disintegration,", undated (Box-folder 47: 3)
    Typescript
  - "Die Diktaturen,", undated (Box-folder 47: 4)
  - "The Fate of Liberal Education,", undated (Box-folder 47: 5)
  - "Die Grundformen,", undated (Box-folder 47: 6)
    Holograph
  - "Helvetius,", undated (Box-folder 47: 7)
  - "Idee zu einer allgemeinen Geschichte in weltbürgerlicher Absicht,", undated
    - Notes (Box-folder 47: 8)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 47: 9)
  - "Individuum und Chaos,", undated (Box-folder 47: 10)
    Holograph and typescript
  - "Die klassische Politik: Ihre Ergebnisse, ihre Schranken,", undated (Box-folder 47: 11)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box-folder 47: 12-18)
  - Notes and research material, undated
    - General (Box-folder 48: 1-5)
    - Aeschylus (Box-folder 48: 6)
    - Antiquity (Box-folder 48: 7)
    - Apocalyptic and gnosis (Box-folder 48: 8)
    - Augustin (Box-folder 48: 9)
    - B (Box-folder 48: 10)
    - Boehme, Jacob (Box-folder 48: 11)
    - Burdach, Konrad (Box-folder 48: 12)
    - Democracies and dictatorships (Box-folder 48: 13)
    - Fascism (Box-folder 49: 1)
    - Gnosticism (Box-folder 49: 2)
    - Hegel (Box-folder 49: 3)
    - International relations (Box-folder 49: 4)
    - Law
      - Constitutional (Box-folder 49: 5)
      - Law and the state (Box-folder 49: 6)
      - Staatsratprotokolle
        - # 1761 (Box-folder 49: 7)
        - # 1771 (Box-folder 49: 8)
        - # 1773 (Box-folder 49: 9)
    - Middle Ages (Box-folder 49: 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 49: 11-12)
    - Moellendorff, W. von (Box-folder 49: 13)
    - Newton, Isaac (Box-folder 49: 14)
    - Paul, Saint - Letters to the Romans and the Corinthians (Box-folder 49: 15)
    - Philosophy
      - Of history (Box-folder 50: 1-3)
      - Of law (Box-folder 50: 4)
    - Revolution (Box-folder 50: 5)
    - Schelling (Box-folder 50: 6)
    - Soviet Union (Box-folder 50: 7)
    - Stirner, Max (Box-folder 50: 8)
    - United States (Box-folder 50: 9)
    - Viatte (Box-folder 50: 10)
    - Völkerwanderung (Box-folder 50: 11)
    - Weber, Max (Box-folder 50: 12)
    - Weltalter (Box-folder 50: 13)
      Includes 11 pages of "What Is History?"
  - "Notizen zu Raum und Zeit in der Kunst,", undated (Box-folder 50: 14)
  - "Ohnmacht und Plannung,", undated (Box-folder 50: 15)
  - "Problem des Missing Link,", undated (Box-folder 50: 16)
  - "Spencer-Kritik,", undated (Box-folder 50: 17)
  - "Der Staat,", undated (Box-folder 50: 18)
  - "The State of Philosophy,", undated (Box-folder 50: 19)
    Lecture notes and outlines. Includes 7 pages of "What Is History?"
  - "Time Problem,", undated (Box-folder 50: 20)
  - "University and Social Order,", undated (Box-folder 50: 21)
    Speech. Outline
  - "Vom Sinn der Demokratie,", undated (Box-folder 50: 22)
  - "Die Welt und der Westen: Eine Einführung in die Theorie der Politik,", undated (Box-folder 50: 23)
  - "Simmel-Apriori,", circa 1921 (Box-folder 51: 1)
  - "Wedekind,", 1921 November-December (Box-folder 51: 2)
  - "Die gesellschaftliche Bestimmtheit soziologischer Erkenntnis," Zeitschrift für Volkswirtschaft und Sozialpolitik, 1922 (Box-folder 51: 3)
    Printed copy
  - Review of B. K. Sarkar, The Political Institutions of the Hindus, 1922 (Box-folder 51: 4)
  - "Wechselwirkung und Gezweiung,", 1922 (Box-folder 51: 5)
    Dissertation. Holograph and typescript
  - Review of Felix Kaufmann, Logik und Rechtswissenschaft. Grundriss eines Systems der reinen Rechtslehre, Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1923 (Box-folder 51: 6)
  - Review of Heinrich Konrad, Das natürliche System der menschlichen Gesellschaft oder die Entstehung der Arten im periodischen System der sozialen Elemente, Zeitschrift für Volkswirtschaft und Sozialpolitik, 1923 (Box-folder 51: 7)
  - Reviews of The Soul of the State (or The Know Thyself), and of Peter Trisca, Prolégomènes à une mécanique sociale, Archiv für Sozialwissenschaft und Sozialpolitik, 1923 (Box-folder 51: 8)
  - "Reine Rechtslehre und Staatslehre," Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1924 (Box-folder 51: 9)
  - Review of Felix Kaufmann, Die Kriterien des Rechts, Archiv für Sozialwissenschaft und Sozialpolitik, 1924 (Box-folder 51: 10)
  - Review of Leo Wittmayer, Osterreichisches Verfassungsrecht, Archiv für Sozialwissenschaft und Sozialpolitik, 1924 (Box-folder 51: 11)
  - "Die Zeit in der Wirtschaft," Archiv für Sozialwissenschaft und Sozialpolitik, 1924 (Box-folder 51: 12)
  - "Uber Max Weber," Deutsche Vierteljahrsschrift für Literaturwissenschaft und Geistesgeschichte, 1925 (Box-folder 51: 13)
  - "Entwicklung der römischen Ständeverfassung," Review of M. Rostovtzeff, Social and Economic History of the Roman Empire, circa 1926 (Box-folder 51: 14)
    Notes and typescript
  - "Die Verfassungsmässigkeit des 18. Amendments zur United States Constitution," Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1926 April (Box-folder 51: 15)
  - "La Follette und die Wisconsin-Idee," Zeitschrift für Politik, 1927 (Box-folder 51: 16)
  - "Kelsen's Pure Theory of Law," Political Science Quarterly, 1927 June (Box-folder 51: 17)
  - "Zur Lehre von der Staatsform," Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1927 July (Box-folder 51: 18)
  - "Landwirtschaftliche Preise und Goldwert," Nationalwirtschaft, circa 1928 (Box-folder 51: 19)
    Translation of an article by John R. Commons. Printed copy
  - Untitled manuscript relating to German political science, circa 1928 (Box-folder 51: 20)
    Notes and holograph
  - "Die ergänzende Bill zum Federal Reserve Act," Nationalwirtschaft, 1928 (Box-folder 51: 21)
    Typescript and printed copy
  - Review of W. F. Bruck, Das Ausbildungsproblem des britischen Beamtes, 1928 (Box-folder 51: 22)
  - "Der Sinn der Erklärung der Menschen- und Bürgerrechte von 1789," Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1928 (Box-folder 51: 23)
    Photocopy of printed copy
  - Uber die Form des amerikanischen Geistes, 1928
    - Holograph (Box-folder 52: 1)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 52: 2)
  - "Konjunkturforschung und Stabilisation des Kapitalismus," Mitteilungen des Verbandes österreichischer Banken und Bankiers, 1928 January 15 (Box-folder 52: 3)
  - "Deutschland und Amerika," Frankfurter Zeitung, 1928 June 10 (Box-folder 52: 4)
    Review of various works. Printed copy
  - Review of W. Boehmer, Pietätlose Schilderung selbsterlebter Tatsachen und zwangsläufiger Konsequenzen aus dem Weltwirtschaftskrieg, 1919-1927, Frankfurter Zeitung, 1928 July 29 (Box-folder 52: 5)
  - Review of E. A. Mowrer, Amerika: Vorbild und Warnung, Frankfurter Zeitung, 1928 August 19 (Box-folder 52: 6)
  - "Zwei Grundbegriffe der Humeschen Gesellschaftslehre," Archiv für angewandte Soziologie, 1928 September (Box-folder 52: 7)
  - Habilitationsschrift, 1928 November 19 (Box-folder 52: 8)
  - Review of Research in the Social Sciences: Its Fundamental Methods and Objectives, edited by Wilson Gee, circa 1929 (Box-folder 52: 9)
  - "To Discuss the Problem of National Types of Mind ...", circa 1929 (Box-folder 52: 10)
  - Reviews of Albert Muntsch and Henry S. Spalding, Introductory Sociology, and of Frank Hamilton Hankins, An Introduction to the Study of Sociology, 1929 (Box-folder 52: 11)
  - Review of B. Mirkin-Getzewitsch, Die rechtstheoretischen Grundlagen des Sowjetstaates, 1929 (Box-folder 52: 12)
  - Review of W. Arendt, Die Staats- und Gesellschaftslehre Alberts des Grössen, 1929 (Box-folder 52: 13)
  - "Die Souveränitätstheorie Dickinsons und die Reine Rechtslehre," Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1929 (Box-folder 52: 14)
  - "Die Transaktion," Archiv für angewandte Soziologie, 1929 January/March (Box-folder 52: 15)
  - Notes and research material for unidentified speeches given in the 1930s (Box-folder 52: 16)
  - "Die amerikanische Theorie vom Eigentum," Archiv für angewandte Soziologie, 1930 (Box-folder 52: 17)
  - "Die amerikanische Theorie vom ordentlichen Rechtsverfahren und von der Freiheit," Archiv für angewandte Soziologie, 1930 (Box-folder 52: 18)
  - "Der Konflikt zwischen Justiz und Verwaltung im Falle der Ehedispense,", 1930 (Box-folder 52: 19)
  - "Das Recht und der Staat," Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1930 (Box-folder 52: 20)
    Translation of H. J. Laski's "Law and the State." Includes a typescript, galley proofs, and a printed copy.
  - Review of Charlotte Lütkens, Staat und Gesellschaft in Amerika, Archiv für Sozialwissenschaft und Sozialpolitik, 1930 (Box-folder 52: 21)
  - Review of E. Jordan, Theory of Legislation: An Essay on the Dynamics of Public Mind, Nationalwirtschaft, 1930 (Box-folder 52: 22)
    Holograph, typescript, galley proofs, and printed copy
  - "Die österreichische Verfassungsreform von 1929," Zeitschrift für Politik, 1930 January (Box-folder 52: 23)
  - "Max Weber,", 1930 June 14 (Box-folder 52: 24)
    Speech, Wiener Soziologische Gesellschaft, Vienna, Austria. Typescript (annotated by Marianne Weber), printed copy, and correspondence with Leopold von Wiese and Marianne Weber
  - "Die Einheit des Rechtes und das soziale Sinngebilde Staat," Internationale Zeitschrift für Theorie des Rechts, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 53: 1)
  - Review of Hellmuth Plessner, Macht und menschliche Natur, Kölner Vierteljahrshefte für Soziologie, circa 1931 (Box-folder 53: 2)
  - "Das Sollen im System Kants," Gesellschaft, Staat und Recht: Festschrift gewidmet Hans Kelsen zum 50. Geburtstage, 1931 (Box-folder 53: 3)
  - "Die Verfassungslehre von Carl Schmitt," Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1931 (Box-folder 53: 4)
  - "Herrschaftslehre und Rechtslehre,", circa 1931-1932 (Box-folder 53: 5)
    Notes, holograph, and typescript
  - Review of Alfred Schütz, Der Sinnhafte Aufbau der sozialen Welt, circa 1932 (Box-folder 53: 6)
  - "Staatslehre als Geisteswissenschaft,", circa 1932 (Box-folder 53: 7)
    Notes, holograph, outline, and typescript
  - Postscript to Ernst Dimnet, Die Kunst des Denkens, 1932 (Box-folder 53: 8)
    Notes, holograph, and printed copy
  - Review of Karl Herrmann, Die Grundlegung des öffentliches Rechts, Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1932 (Box-folder 53: 9)
    Galley proofs
  - Review of Ernst Gerhard Jacob, Daniel Defoe: Essay on Projects (1697), Archiv für Rechtsphilosophie, 1932 April (Box-folder 53: 10)
  - "Die Rechtmassigkeit der Regiebeiträge zum Abrechnungsamt und die Novelle zum Vorkriegsschuldengesetze, BGB 1, Nr. 7, vom Jahre 1932,", 1932 May 26 (Box-folder 53: 11)
    Notes, holograph, typescript, and correspondence with Max Hitschmann
  - Review of Heinz O. Ziegler, Die moderne Nation, Zeitschrift für die gesamte Staatswissenschaft, 1932 December (Box-folder 53: 12)
    Galley proofs and printed copy
  - "Forschungsbericht über die Rassentheorie,", circa 1933 (Box-folder 53: 13)
    Notes, holograph, outline, and typescript of first chapter. Includes an outline entitled "Stand der Rassenfrage," perhaps for a speech on 27 March (1929 or 1935?) entitled "Der Stand der Rassenfrage in der Staats- und Gesellschaftslehre"
  - Review of Bernhard Laum, Die geschlossene Wirtschaft: Soziologische Grundlegung des Autarkieproblems, Zeitschrift für Nationalökonomie, circa 1933 (Box-folder 53: 14)
  - Review of Hans Steingräber, Deutsche Gemeinschaftsphilosophie der Gegenwart, circa 1933 (Box-folder 53: 15)
  - Review of Walter Hamel, Das Wesen des Staatsgebietes, Blätter für deutsche Philosophie, circa 1933 (Box-folder 53: 16)
  - "Thesen zu dem Referat Rasse und Staat,", circa 1933 (Box-folder 53: 17)
    Outline, holograph, and typescript
  - "Uber Rasse und Staat, ", circa 1933 (Box-folder 53: 18)
  - "Grundbegriffe der Staatslehre und des österreichischen Verfassungsrechtes,", 1933 (Box-folder 53: 19)
    Outline for a projected book and letter from Springer-Verlag
  - Rasse und Staat, 1933
    - Notes (Box-folder 53: 20)
    - Holograph (Box-folder 53: 21)
    - Typescript
      - Part I (Box-folder 53: 22)
      - Part II (Box-folder 53: 23)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 54: 1)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 54: 2)
  - Die Rassenidee in der Geistesgeschichte von Ray bis Carus, 1933
    See also "Thesen über Rasse und Staat"
    - Notes (Box-folder 54: 3)
    - Holograph (Box-folder 54: 4)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 54: 5)
  - Review of Reinhold Horneffer, Die Entstehung des Staates, Blätter für deutsche Philosophie, 1933 (Box-folder 54: 6)
    Typescript, galley proofs, and printed copy
  - Review of Franz W. Jerusalem, Gemeinschaft und Staat, Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1933 (Box-folder 54: 7)
    Typescript and galley proofs
  - Review of Günter Namslau, Rechtfertigung des Staates bei Christian Wolff, Zentralblatt für die juristische Praxis, 1933 (Box-folder 54: 8)
  - "Vollstreckungsrechtshilfe,", 1933 (Box-folder 54: 9)
    Typescript and letter to Dr. Schlemmer
  - "Amerikakunde," Frankfurter Zeitung, 1933 March 26 (Box-folder 54: 10)
  - "Nachwort,", circa 1934 (Box-folder 54: 11)
    Afterword to unpublished work by Ernst Grünwald. Notes, outline, holograph, and typescript
  - Review of A. E. Hoche, Das Rechtsgefühl in Justiz und Politik, Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1934 (Box-folder 54: 12)
  - Review of A. Zimmern, Nationality and Government, and The Prospects of Democracy, Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1934 (Box-folder 54: 13)
  - Review of D. Schindler, Verfassungsrecht und soziale Struktur, Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1934 (Box-folder 54: 14)
  - Review of Max Rumpf, Politische und soziologische Staatslehre, Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, 1934 (Box-folder 54: 15)
  - "Rassenidee und -wissenschaft: Ein Beitrag zur Klärung," Kölnische Zeitung, 1934 January 21 (Box-folder 54: 16)
  - "Was versteht man eigentlich unter Autarkie,", 1934 March 8 (Box-folder 54: 17)
    Speech, Deutsche Handelskammer in Wien, Vienna, Austria. Outline
  - "Nochmals, Rasse und Staat in der Staatslehre: Erwiderung," Reichsverwaltungsblatt, 1934 March 10 (Box-folder 54: 18)
    Printed copy and letter to Otto Koellreuter
  - "Verfassungsgebung für Osterreich," Wiener Zeitung, 1934 April 27 (Box-folder 54: 19)
    Outline and printed copy
  - "Neues Kammersystem im Spiegel der Geschichte," Wiener Zeitung, Holograph and printed copy, 1934 May 5 (Box-folder 54: 20)
    Holograph and printed copy
  - "Der autoritäre Staatskern," Wiener Zeitung, 1934 May 13 (Box-folder 54: 21)
  - "Rasse und Staat,", 1934 May 22-26 (Box-folder 54: 22)
    Paper, 14th Congress of the Deutsche Gesellschaft für Psychologie, Tübingen, West Germany. Printed copy
  - "Todesreigen 1934," Wiener Zeitung, 1934 November 1 (Box-folder 54: 23)
    Printed copy (signed: Dr. E.V.)
  - Review of Mélanges offerts à Ernest Mahaim, par ses collègues, ses amis, ses élèves, Liège, 5 novembre 1935, circa 1935 (Box-folder 54: 24)
  - "Auszugsweise Ubersetzung der Entscheidungen des Obersten Gerichtshofes der Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika in der Goldklauselfrage vom 18. Februar 1935," Mitteilungen des Verbandes österreichischer Banken und Bankiers (Box-folder 54: 25)
    Translation of legal decisions of the United States Supreme Court regarding the gold clause. Typescript, printed copy, and letter from Assen Hartenau